T. Hobbes, "Leviathan"
Hey, did you see that stream yesterday?
Yeah, it was so good!
What? A drama? What was it about?
I'm curious now!
To protect my precious friends,
I must protect the class.
Because if the class is protected,
my friends will be protected.
But...
That's not who I really am.
During that incident in
middle school, I messed up.
That's why I can't afford to make
the same mistake in this class.
And the answer I arrived at for that...
was...
Horikita...
Shut the hell up, would you?
But in the end...
I made the same mistake.
We're here.
What did you want to talk about?
Kiyotaka?
If we're discussing the special exam,
I thought it would be best to have him along.
He's the team captain, after all.
Got it.
So?
I thought up a way to get
information on Class A.
Follow one of them around?
No.
Get Katsuragi-kun from Class A on our side.
What do you mean?
He might hold a grudge against Sakayanagi
for expelling Yahiko, who admired him.
Since then, he's been isolated within
the class and lost all standing.
He and Sakayanagi are enemies, it's true.
But do you think he'd betray his class
just to embarrass Sakayanagi-san?
He would certainly need
compensation, of course.
Do we have something like that available?
If we make it to Class A, we'll issue
Katsuragi the right to transfer to our class.
We'd need twenty million points for that!
If the whole class worked
together, we could save it up.
I can't imagine most students
accepting that bargain.
We're still only Class C.
And if his betrayal were discovered,
he'd be the next one expelled.
We'd need to rack up those
twenty million points quickly.
I'm not denying that he has
potential as an informant.
But the plan you proposed won't work.
If we don't do anything,
we won't get any information.
I don't think this plan will
get us any information, either.
If you get a new idea,
let me know about it.
Kiyotaka, will you help me?
I've arranged to meet with Katsuragi soon.
And if I did that,
what would be in it for me?
We'd let you join our class.
Once we made it to Class A, we'd save up—
I'll pass.
Your class will never save
up twenty million points.
However, it's true that I harbor
tremendous anger toward Sakayanagi.
She hasn't told anyone her
five genuine subjects,
but if you don't mind best guesses,
I'll happily give them to you.
You mean it?
But what would you want in exchange?
All I really want is the
defeat of Sakayanagi.
Chess, English, math.
These three are unquestionably genuine.
Most likely after that are modern
literature and mental math.
Meanwhile, jump rope and dodgeball, which
require a large number of participants,
are most likely fakes.
Kiyotaka, this could be our ticket!
No, you won't beat her with
this minor amount of help.
If I hold back, it might help you
fight on even terms, at least.
The only fields in which I can
help you are mental math
and perhaps jump rope, on the
off-chance that it's chosen.
With Sakayanagi on her guard, do you
think she'll allow you to participate?
In Class A, the only ones skilled at
mental math are me and one other.
If I'm not chosen, chalk it up to bad
luck and be resigned to your fate.
Let's tell Horikita.
No. She'll be angry if she
learns we went behind her back.
Let me decide when to tell her.
Okay.
Special Lunch Set                         Cheese Gratin                            Tofu Salad
What is it?
Could you come meet with me immediately?
Special Lunch Set                         Cheese Gratin                            Tofu Salad
I have a bad feeling about this.
Barley miso?
I didn't know you were a good cook.
It's hardly worth bragging about.
Now, you've eaten, haven't you?
May I come to the subject at hand?
I appreciate the effort, but please
don't use this method again.
Very well. I'll think up another way.
That's not what I meant, actually...
I thought up what I feel to be an ideal
plan for Class C going into this.
I'd like your opinion on it.
You've really exposed our
whole class with this data.
This is the answer I came up
with over a week of thinking.
RPS  Best Candidate: Ike Kanji  Chance of Success: 50%
Piano  Best Candidate: Horikita Suzune  Chance of Success: 60%
Tennis  Best Candidate: Kushida Kikyo  Chance of Success: 55%
Ping-Pong  Best Candidate: Sudo Takeshi  Chance of Success: 60%
Final Special Exam Class A Subjects
(Chance of success with best candidate)
Chess
Best Candidate: None  Chance of Success: 40%
Modern Lit Test
50 minutes
Rules: Compete over year's worth of subject matter.
Captain rules: Able to answer one question in test-taker's stead.
Social Studies Test
50 minutes
Rules: Compete over questions based on a year's worth of geography,
history, and civics subject matter.
Captain rules: Able to answer one question in test-taker's stead.
Volleyball
Time limited 3 sets to 10 points
Rules: Standard volleyball rules.
Captain rules: Able to swap out three players at chosen time.
Math Test: 50 minutes
Rules: Compete over year's worth of subject matter.
Captain rules: Able to answer one question in test-taker's stead.
English Test: 50 minutes
Rules: Compete over year's worth of subject matters
Captain rules: Able to answer one question in test-taker's stead.
I have no objections to the content.
But may I make one request?
What is it?
I'd like you to take on the chess
competition Class A requested.
Me?
It's true that someone will
need to practice it, but...
Why me?
You seem the most suited for me to teach.
Very well.
How will we practice, then?
I was thinking we'd
practice online overnight.
That way, no one will see us.
You think we can beat Class A this way?
I don't think they're an unbeatable opponent.
That's what this data made me think.
I'm going to keep leaving things to you.
All that's left is...
Wait a moment, Hirata-kun.
I'd like to confirm one thing with you.
I don't currently plan to use
you on the day of the test.
But if we end up with a subject that
requires a large number of people,
will you at least give
the bare minimum effort?
You're not going to tell me?
I guess we don't stand a chance, huh?
With Hirata-kun acting like that...
And with so little time before the test...
Wait, Hirata-kun!
Please, Hirata-kun.
We really need you for this!
Please...
Could you please leave me alone?
I can't do that!
Then will you bring Yamauchi-kun back?
Talking with you is a waste of time.
I can go now, right?
Ow...
If you won't leave me alone—
Well, well.
Still skulking around, are we?
This is quite an ugly side you're showing.
Oh, dear.
Don't mind me.
By all means, continue.
I suppose you want something from me, too?
As I already possess everything I want,
the most I'd ask from you would be...
to kindly remain out of my sight.
Just shut up.
You don't know what I'm going through!
I certainly don't.
Nor do I want to.
S-Stop this, Koenji-kun!
Hirata-kun didn't do anything wrong!
Oh, do forgive me.
But you'd be best off forgetting
about your boy Hirata there.
He's broken.
I've had just about enough
out of you, Koenji!
If you come after me, I won't hold back.
If you don't want her, perhaps I'll take her.
Wh-What?!
P-Please, let me down!
I can't do that.
You're heartbroken, and physically harmed.
I'd like to mend all that ails you.
E-Er... I... I'm not harmed at all!
No need to worry, now.
Despite appearances, I'm really quite gentle.
Let me go!
Put me down!
I fear I can't do that.
Why?!
I already have you, you see.
No! Put me down!
You still have call to quarrel with me, then?
You're doing this to hurt me, aren't you?
No.
You're the one hurting those around you.
At the very lease, I refuse to let
such a good-hearted girl go neglected.
Why don't you just disappear?
Hirata-kun...
You'd be best served by
leaving him alone for today.
Hirata.
Why can't you people just leave me alone?
Are you going to shove me and run
away, like you did with Mii-chan?
I'm too tired.
I don't have the energy to run anymore.
So, what did you want to talk about?
I want to hear what you have to say.
You continue to resent the expulsion of
Yamauchi, and refuse to work with the class.
I want to know what happened that
formed that worldview of yours.
What good would it do for me to tell you?
You'll have told me.
There's a terrifyingly vast
darkness behind your eyes.
It all started when I was in middle school.
A good friend of mine became
a target for bullying.
I wanted to save him.
But I was afraid of becoming a target myself,
so I just sat back and watched.
Then, one day...
My friend tried to jump to his death.
They managed to save his life,
but he never recovered,
and remains in a coma.
I'm the one who drove him to it.
It wasn't solely your fault.
That's true.
But bystanders share the guilt.
I thought my friend's suicide
attempt would be the end of it.
But it wasn't.
After that happened, I saw the
greatest depths of human darkness.
My classmates found a new
target for their bullying.
I couldn't believe it.
Someone who'd been a bystander until then
became their new target.
And even classmates who only tolerated
the bullying began to join in.
Once the bottom rung of
the hierarchy disappears,
the student just above
them is now on the bottom.
It's a law of nature, in a way.
I was determined to stop it.
So I tried to control them through fear.
You did?
I employed violence.
No one was willing to hit me back.
I created a hierarchy with me on top,
and everyone else at the bottom.
If any conflict came up, I dished out the
same punishment and pain to both sides.
I think I destroyed the entire
class year as a result.
The students stopped smiling and
conducted themselves like robots.
And that's why you didn't like seeing
Yamauchi singled out among our class?
In the end, I couldn't protect Yamauchi-kun.
I was incapable of bringing
our class together.
To protect one person, I tried
to rule through fear once more.
It's not Horikita's fault
that Yamauchi was expelled.
It isn't mine, either.
Do you realize that?
Yeah. It was inevitable.
There was nothing any of us could have done.
That isn't true.
Yamauchi's expulsion, Hirata,
was your fault.
If you really wanted to save him,
you should have done
whatever it took to do it.
But I did everything!
I just couldn't save him!
Ichinose of Class B didn't sacrifice anyone.
But that's...
Her situation was special.
She had all those private
points that made it possible!
Then the issue was your inability
to spearhead a similar initiative.
That's unreasonable!
Yes, but that doesn't matter.
That's the path that you'd chosen.
Your belief that everyone could be saved
is a private fantasy of your own making.
But if you want to continue
to feel that way,
then when you fail,
you need to take on all the blame.
That's the dedication that
that cause requires.
I—
I was under a mistaken impression.
I thought you were a person of character,
whom our classmates respected.
But that's not true.
A shallow, helpless student who boasts
about wanting to do the impossible...
That's who you are, Hirata Yosuke.
How long do you expect
to remain in your dream?
This is who you really are, isn't it?
Those are horrifyingly merciless, cold words.
You're free to want what you want.
But if you want to save everyone,
the only way is to fight to the end,
and struggle to the limits
of what is available.
If, after all that, someone is still expelled,
you must resign yourself, accept it,
and continue to walk forward.
It's all too cruel.
Hesitation on your part now will lead to
more and more of your classmates being lost.
That's why you need to keep looking
forward and walking to the very end.
If you do that, then when it's all over,
you'll find many students
standing right behind you.
Do I really have to bear the
entire burden and keep walking?
Then where am I supposed to show weakness?
When you're struggling, you can ask
your other classmates for help.
You can show weakness to
whoever you choose to rely on.
It doesn't matter if they're
ahead of or behind you.
I... Is someone like me...
really suited to walk in front of everyone?
The person you are now
can safely walk in front of them.
Thank you.
Thank you, Ayanokoji-kun.
That should do it.
Morning!
Morning.
Pretty warm out today, huh?
G-Good morning, Hirata-kun.
Good morning.
I'm sorry about yesterday!
I was absolutely horrible to you, Mii-chan.
You've been trying and trying to talk to me.
I'm sorry I ignored you.
Th-Th-That's okay...
I wasn't bothered at all.
Good morning, everyone!
H-Hirata-kun?
And... I'm sorry!
I realize it might be too late for apologies,
but if you're all right with it,
I'd like to contribute to the class again.
Hirata-kun!
What's come over you?
We've been waiting!
Yeah!
What happened here?
Good morning, Horikita-san.
Y-Yes... good morning.
I don't think I was wrong to object
to your treatment of the class vote.
I see.
But what you did wasn't wrong, either.
Rather... it was one correct option.
That's a significant change
in perspective from yesterday.
I'm going to do the best I can to recover
the trust you've all lost in me.
Checkmate.
I have a long way to go.
You've acquired an impressive amount
of mastery in quite a short time.
I still couldn't win without
you taking it easy on me.
No one can beat me when I'm not holding back.
You're awfully confident.
Ayanokoji Kiyotaka
It's not confidence. It's experience.
We'll call it off here in
preparation for tomorrow.
I suppose.
I'll see you tomorrow, then.
Right.
Final Special Exam
Team Captain Meeting Spot
Kaneda-kun's not here yet.
Ryuen-kun?
What are you doing here?
What's got you so upset?
I see.
It seems we made an assumption
that whoever had protection points
would serve as team captain.
If the team captain is absent,
it's only natural that someone
else should fill in for them.
Isn't it?
Well, gosh.
Watching Ryuen-kun, back to the wall,
without a protection point...
It appears their competition
will be quite amusing, as well.
Now that we're all here, shall we proceed?